# Uma Rama Linga Murthy Marthi

Business Intelligence, Data Science Consultant

☑ ram.marthi@gmail.com, 🕈 Chennai, India, 📞 +91 9000364152, 🗘 /RamMarthi9, in in/rmarthi-521057138



# About Me

As a seasoned cloud-based Data Scientist, BI Developer with over a decade of experience, I have successfully built, deployed, and maintained over 50 dashboards and led numerous data science projects. My expertise spans across SQL, Python, R-Language, ML, DL, AI, NLP, CV, Qlik, PowerBI and Tableau. I am passionate about collaborating with industry-leading professionals and am particularly drawn to opportunities that involve addressing the most critical business challenges.

#### Areas of Specialization

- · Statistical Data Analysis
- · ETL · Business Intelligence · Machine Learning · Deep Learning
- Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- · Computer Vision
- · DevOps · MLOps · Data Pipelines · Scrum Master
- Python R-Language

#### Personal

Nationality: India Date Of Birth: 10/03/1987 Place Of Birth: Hyderabad Languages: English, Hindi, Telugu, Tamil

#### **DEGREES**

2008

2023 **Data Science and Engineering** 



2010 **Finance and Marketing** PGDM., · SSIM, Hyderabad 🏛

> **Mechanical Engineering** B.TECH., · DMSSVHCE, Machili-

patnam 🏛

### **SKILLS**

Ansi-SQL,PL-SQL,T-SQl Python, R-Language ML, DL, AI, NLP, CV QlikSense,QlikView AWS-S3,Sagemaker Alteryx, Power BI, Tableau





# Work Experience

#### 2021-Present CMA CGM GBS INDIA LTD

Consultant Manager · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to generate business use cases with application of Machine learning on global customer data base · Responsible to maintain Global Partner Data Management Dashboards and related dimensions · Lead Global CDM Analytics and data science initiatives managing a team of data analysts.

2018-2020 LATENTVIEW ANALYTICS LTD

LEAD DATA ANALYST · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to collect requirements, project planning, execution and delivery of analytics solutions to clients spread across Insurance and Auto industries.

2016-2018 SCINTEL TECHNOLOGIES LTD

SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to collect requirements, execution and delivery of Business Intelligence solutions to clients from Healthcare Industry.

GAFFNEY-KROESE SUPPLY INDIA PVT. LTD. 2012-2016

Business Analyst · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to maintain databases in SQL and prepare reports as per management needs.

2011-2012 ZENITH ENERGY SERVICES PVT LTD.

Assistant Manager-Renewable Energy · Hyderabad, India 💡 Responsible to conduct MNRE based policy study on biomass and baggasse cogeneration plants across India.

2010-2011 **NOVUS GREEN ENERGY SYSTEMS PVT LTD.** 

> AREA MANAGER-CHATTISGARH · Raipur, India 💡 Responsible for business development.

# VITAL DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

- · 2024: Investment Tracking PowerBI Dashboard
- 2024: House Price Prediction with Machine Learning in Kaggle
- 2023: Bookings Prediction with Deep Learning and Data Replication with GANs
- 2023: Customer Churn Prediction in Shipping Industry with Machine Learning
- 2023: Computer Vision based scene text extraction model to extract data for twitter data extraction.
- · 2022: NLP Based AI Tool for penny stocks recommendations

Ram Marthi ☑ Chennai 9 India 📞 +91 9000 364152 @ ram.marthi@gmail.com





😂 rgfoufniom

**CMA CGM** 











